recorded in
зафиксирована в
1689,
1689 году
yes, the modern Moscow
да Московская современная Московская
region, the village of kopche, it was a ritual of the
область деревня копче э было ритуальное
young Virgin. Yes, that’s what the Elders write,
юной Девы Да так и пишет Да что Старцы
well, really, the Elders, for ritual purposes, harvest
ну реально вот Старцы в обрядовых целях
anything for to
жно что угодно для
increase yes, to increase
для для повышения да для повышения
the fertility of the Earth, the Council
плодородия Земли постановили Совет
of Elders decided to, for ritual purposes, the young  a
Старейшин э в ритуальных целях молодую
girl like 14
девушку типа 14
years old
лет
Hello Hello, I think I’ve
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я вас вроде
already seen you I think you too I think you’re
уже видела Я вас тоже вроде Вы
from Where I’m from Omsk And you I’m from
откуда Я из Омска А вы Я из
Tomsk from Tomsk with the British flag in the background
Томска из Томска что на фоне британского
Well because I’ve been living in London for 18 years,
флага Ну потому что уже 18 лет живу в
in 2 years we’ll
Лондоне через 2 года будет
have a university If you  you know,
у нас университет Если вы знаете да что
Tomsk is quite a student town and
Томск довольно студенческий городок и
our University with
Наш Университет с
Cambridge has an exchange program, I
кембриджем программы обмена имеет я
went on the exchange program, won and
поехал по программа обмена выиграл и
decided to stay in
решил остаться в
Britain. That is, you study. Well, if I’m 18
Британии То есть вы учитесь Ну если я 18
years old there, then I haven’t studied for a long time,
лет там то я уже давно не учусь
really, yes. How the hell do I know?  and
правда да Откуда же я знаю блин можно и
at the age of 90 go to study no I studied 18
в 90 лет пойти учиться нет Я учился 18
years ago I
лет назад
graduated very
отучился оче
cool now I’m a university teacher now
круто сейчас Я преподаватель сейчас
teaching
университета преподаю
anthropology Oh this is very cool And you
антропологию О это очень классно А вы
know it’s super but he’s not really an anthropologist
знаете супер но он не совсем антрополог
he’s a pale
он пале
anthropologist Well yes yes he’s at Moscow State University teaching
антрополог Ну да да он вй в МГУ препода
it’s a little
это немного
like  you know, for example, there is a
это как знаете например есть чем
difference between anthropology and Pali
отличается антропология от пали
anthropology. Yes, look, this is the same as the
антропологии Да смотрите это так же как
difference between a surgeon and a pathological
отличается хирург от патолого
anatomist.
анатома
Wow, that is, anthropology
Вау а то есть антропология она живых
studies living people. Yes, living populations. Yes, and
людей изучает Да живые популяции Да и
so on, and paleoanthropology
так дальше а палеоантропология
is fossils. Uh-huh. That is, for example, he
ископаемые Угу То есть он например
dug up the skull of a Neanderthal man. Dalas explained this way
выкопал череп неандертальца далас так
just like a surgeon is different
объяснили так же как хирург отличается
from a poto Well, yes, because so we
от пото Ну так да Потому что так вот мы
are, there is a small nuance there. It’s
отча есть небольшие там один нюанс
just that, in principle, it cuts something else.
Просто в принципе режет и то-то другой
But there is one small nuance, and that’s how it
Но есть один нюанс маленький такой вот и
turns out in paleoanthropology, they
получается на палеоантропология они
study populations that lived
исследуют популяции которые жили
there, for example, hundreds of thousands  years ago and so
например там сотни тысяч лет назад и так
on there to historical people and so
дальше там до исторических людей и так
on in We study modern
дальше во Мы изучаем современные
human populations, tell us what’s interesting about owl
людей расскажите что интересного сов
populations In modern human populations
популяциях В современных популяциях
Have you noticed, let’s say you
Вот вы замечали скажем вы в Омск
were born in Omsk there in Omsk or came from
родились там в Омске или приехали из
Omsk born in Omsk Yes, and were there, for example,
Омска родилась в Омск Да а были например
where  - in central
где-то в средней полосе
Russia there is no
России нет
Okay, well, well, on TV, you
Хорошо давайте так ну по телевизору Вы
saw many Russians there, you
видели же там многих россиян вот
noticed the Volga region, the Urals, the Moscow
замечали Поволжье Урал Московская
region, a certain interesting
область определённое такое интересное
structure of the jaws. That's how Yeltsin was seen,
строение Челюсти Вот как Ельцин видели
remember Yeltsin was also
помните Ельцин ещё
found Well, everyone has a different structure of
застали Ну у всех разное строение
the jaws I thought these were individual
Челюсти Я думала это индивидуальные
characteristics, no  wait, here's a photo and video,
особенности нет подожди вот фото-видео
we saw
видели
Yeltsin Well, yes, yes, yes, he has quite a
Ельцина Ну да да да у него довольно
large skull
такое какое-то крупная черепная коробка
Yes And this slightly protruding
Да И вот такая немного выпирающая
jaw Well, the Habsburgs had it too.
челюсть Ну у Габсбургов тоже была
Excuse me, why was it a little different?
Извините меня че габу немножко другая
Yes, that
была да так вот
would be This defect was here and there  exactly
бы Это дефект был вот а тут именно
the phenotype is
фенотип
such an honor it is not current My
такой честь она есть не токов У моей
friend had this jaw and even the
подруги была Вот такая челюсть и даже
operation was done like this Look, the thing is
операцию делали вот так Смотрите дело в
that
том что
it is called in anthropology Yes
это называется в антропологии Да
andropharm
андрофарм
it is inherent in those former tribes that
он присущ тем бывшим племенам которые
in
в
approximately the Volga Oka Mesopotamia
приблизительно Волго окском Междуречье
this is what we call it in anthropology
это так называется у нас в антропологии
that is, approximately in the Aki
то есть приблизительно в бассейне Аки
Volga basin in the Upper reaches of the modern
Волги в Верхних течениях современная
Moscow region Ivanovo
Московская область Ивановская
Vologda Yaroslavl these Yes,
Вологодская Ярославская вот эти Да вот
uh, there, according to
ээ там ещё по
the memoirs of Herodotus, the Andropharm tribes lived as
ээ воспоминаниям геродота жили племена
Russians, yes That is, we
андрофарм русскими да То есть у нас
have different populations among the Russians. Yes, for
среди русских есть разные популяции Да
example, in the Kuban, the Russians are
например на Кубани русские это
Russified Ukrainians So  there are those
русифицированные украинцы То есть те
Zaporozhye Zaporozhye Cossacks who were
запорожские запорожские казаки которых
resettled in Kuban Yes, that’s why the
переселили на Кубань Да поэтому
anthropological Kuban
антропологический Кубанский
type is
тип
that they mixed with the Turks In the
что они же перемешались с турками В
end, they didn’t
итоге не не
mix where there were
перемешались где были
changes, they
перемени
didn’t take Turkish
реза не брали турецких
wives Well, like there was a war with the Ottomans
жён Ну типа там же была война с османами
No, well, to take a wife you have to come
Нет ну что чтоб взять жену надо приехать
to  to take a Turkish wife, you need to
чтобы взять турецкую жену надо куда-то
come somewhere to Turkey and bring this wife
приехать в Турцию и эту жену привезти
from there, well, first you need to start
оттуда как ну для начала нужно войну там
some kind of war there and then
какую-нибудь развязать а потом там уже
take it there no no no look no
забирать хоче Не не нет смотри никакие
Yes, the Cossacks
Да казаки ни с какими там турецкими
didn’t marry any Turkish wives. This is what  -that's nonsense
жёнами они не женились Это какой-то бред
I'm hearing for the first time, and it's
Я Впервые слышу да и оно даже
not even anthropological because the
антропологический не это потому что
Turks are Oguz Turks, they have Oguz
турки - это тюрки огузы у них огузский
anthropological, they include Turkmens,
антропологические к ним входят туркмены
Azerbaijanis and these geese in Moldova,
азербайджанцы и эти в Молдове гусы вот у
they can clearly see one
них чётко прослеживается один
anthropological about them, they also
антропологический про них ещё
say such a beautiful
говорят такой красивый
Cossack there with  As they
казак там с Как как
say with the panda, the Cossack mother Turey with
говорят с панду казак мама турей с
Turenko means appearance, that is,
туренко имеет в виду внешность то есть
handsome Kaza
красивый каза
dark hair black eyebrows but with a
тёмные волосы чёрные брови но с
hump so tall and
горбинкой такой с туреччини высокий
handsome this is the first time I’ve heard such
красивый это впервые я такой
an anthropological one
антропологический
no so look so the fact is
слышал нене так смотри так вот Дело в
that yes uh those Russians who  lived
том что да ээ те россияне которые жили
This is the Moscow Vologda region
Вот это Московская Вологодская область
Yes, these are the Heirs of the andropharm tribes,
Да это Наследники племён
it can manifest itself in your
оно может проявляться у вашей например
friend, for example, also yes to us Why Because
подружки также да наме Почему Потому что
Omsk Yes, this is not the territory and Tomsk where the
Омск Да это не территория и Томск где
Russians originally lived Yes, they
русские жили изначально Да они там по
came there from different countries, even though we all come here
приезжали из разных хоть мы же все сюда
as if from  Yes, that’s why in Omsk in Omsk Yes,
как бы по Да поэтому в Омске в Омске Да
there are different anthropological types, just like
есть разные антропологические типы как и
in my Tomsk Yes, there are Pavoloki Kubansky
в моём Томске Да есть паволоки Кубанский
And so on Yes, that’s why your
И так дальше Да поэтому вот ваша
girlfriend has an anthropological
подружка она у неё вот антропологический
type, it’s clear Yes, you have more of your
тип это понятно Да вот у вас более у вас
relatives Where is
родственники Откуда родом
Ivanova Ivanova from exactly and  all from Ivanovo
Иванова Иванова точно и все из Иванова
or
или
not no only about the grandmothers I can
нет нет только про бабки могу
tell my grandfather I can’t say in my opinion
сказать деду не могу сказать по-моему
everything is from Siberia even his
все из Сибири даже
grandfather got his last name from
фамилия получается у деда у него по
the name of his village which is in
названию его деревни которая вот в
Siberia
Сибири
Novgorodians I can’t say where the great-
новгородцев я негу сказать откуда бы
grandmother was from Ivanov and they are here  we
прабабка она была из Иванова и они сюда
moved because my grandmother had
переехали потому что у моей бабушки была
asthma and the climate there was too humid and so
астма а там климат слишком влажный и вот
they arrived. Or maybe from the war I know
они приехали А может быть от войны знаю
Ivanova, well, there somewhere not far
Иванова это ну там где-то там недалеко
there in the Moscow region I know I
там Подмосковье Я знаю
know we were we were in practice just the
знаю мы были мы были на практике как раз
anthropological Ivanova Well, the thing is  the fact
антропологической Иванова Ну Дело в том
that they took us from Tomsk. My
что из Томска нас возили Мы у меня
dissertation was just on This is
диссертация была как раз по Вот это
Andropharm and we researched, uh, we took
андрофарм и мы исследовали ээ брали мы
measurements. We came to the Ivanovo region in
замеры Приезжали в ивановскую область в
the villages, yes. Because why in the villages
сёла именно да Потому что почему в сёла
in the cities
в городах уже может быть перемешаны в
can people from Ukraine already be mixed in the cities?  from
городах могли бы люди из Украины из
Belarus to come there from Lithuania And in the
белорусси приехать там из Литвы А в
villages in the villages Yes, there is an even more
сёлах в деревнях Да ещё более
autochthonous population Yes, we have them I have
автохтонное население Да мы им У меня
just the research Ivanovo
как раз вот исследование Ивановская
region Yes, there is an anthropological
область Да содержится антропологический
type of Jaws, up to
тип Челюсти содержится до
73% of the population is contained That is, the rest are
73% населения Вот то есть остальные
some kind of impurities Maybe there are Turkic
какие-то примеси Может там тюркских
Maybe there  Fino Ugric and some, but
Может там фино угорских да каких-то но
this is the largest concentration in
это самая большая концентрация в
androphobia Jaws in the Moscow region
андрофобия Челюсти в Московской области
in villages, yes, that is, there it is somewhere,
в деревнях да то есть там вот оно где-то
they had such a core Well, that is, it is
ядро такое у них было Ну то есть это
such a rather powerful jaw Yes,
такая довольно мощная челюсть Да мощная
such a powerful jaw is a little bit The thing is  that uh
челюсть такая немножко Дело в том что ээ
it’s like
оно как бы у
Andropharm has
андрофарм
such a predatory reflex they uh ate
такой хищнический Рефлекс они э-э ели
raw meat so that is they didn’t
сырое мясо так то есть они не ещё во
eat raw meat back in the time of Herodotus it’s not
времена геродотов пил ели сырое мясо не
wrong when you look most of the tribes have
не так когда смотрите большинство племён
already switched to cooking Yes uh
уже перешло на приготовление пищи Да ээ
Andropharm
андрофарм
uh certain
ээ определённые как бы
parts  now now now I’ll say this,
части сейчас сейчас сейчас я скажу так
look. The fact is that those individuals
вот смотри Дело в том что и те э особи
who were evolutionary, those individuals
которые вот эволюционного те особи у
whose jaws were weak, they did not
которых была слаба челюсть они не
survive, but it was these ones with
выживали да выживали именно вот эти с
such protruding jaws that survived, hard, it
такими оттопыренными челюстями
sounds very strange, by the way, especially when you consider that even there
звучит особенно если учесть что даже там
no matter how modern chimpanzees are, they are
какие ни шимпанзе современные они с
happy to eat fried mice there after fires, they
удовольствием там после пожаров жрут
really love this business,
именно жареных мышей очень это дело
so Andropharm
любят так что и у андрофарм
and
и
by the way don’t, well, they didn’t even think about the economy before,
кстати не ну тут же раньше про экономику
you know, before everyone
не думали понимаете раньше каждый
survived in the Moscow region and in the
выживал э в Московской области да в
villages of the Moscow region in the villages of the
деревнях Московской в деревнях
Moscow region  cannibalism
Московской области каннибализм
was recorded until the 15th century Yes, there is also a
фиксировался до XV века ещё Да ещё есть
decree uh Perhaps there was some period of
указ ээ Возможно да какой-то период
famine there and
голода там да
such rituals for ritual purposes Yes, the
такое обрядовых в обрядовых целях Да
fact is that back at the end of the 15th
дело в том что ещё в конце в конце XV
century Yes Peter I issued a decree on the
века Да Пётр I издавал указ о
flogging and execution of those who engage in
порке и казни тех кто занимается
cannibalism  on the territory of
каннибализмом на территории там вот
this Moscow Posad there was Well,
этого Московского Посада было Ну
probably it wasn’t ritual [ __ ] after all,
наверное это было всё-таки не ритуальная
because damn the toile
фигня потому что блин туаль
would have been ritually eaten and recorded, look, that is,
бы были да зафиксированы смотри то есть
Take Well, now you’re just saying
Возьмите Ну вы сейчас просто говорите
look, you look at Drobyshevsky, yes, you
посмотри Вы дробышевского да смотрите Вы
watched the wine lectures Yes, on pale
вино смотрели лекции Да по пале
anthropology  Look a little bit at
антропологии Посмотрите немножко по
history Yes Google
истории Да Погугли
that’s the name of
так называется
bondage Look it’s not
кабали Смотри не
cannibalism that the decrees of Peter I will be preserved Yes
каннибализм сохранятся указы Петра I Да
and you can get acquainted with their CSR
и можно ознакомиться с ихними ксро
copies Or you can look at the original
копиями А можно и посмотреть оригинал
If you are some kind of scientist Yes that’s what it
Если вы учёный какой-то Да так
says there Yes what is recorded on the territory
вот там сказано Да что на территории вот
In 1600
зафиксировано В 1600
in 9th  year
в 9м году
yes Moscow modern Moscow
да Московская современная Московская
region village kopche uh it was a ritual of the
область деревня копче ээ было ритуальное
young Virgin Yes, that’s what it says Yes that the Elders, well,
юной Девы Да так и пишет Да что Старцы
really, here are the starts for ritual purposes
ну реально вот старты в обрядовых целях
E anything for for
Э что угодно для для
higher for increasing yes for increasing the
повыше для повышения да для повышения
fertility of the earth the Council of
плодородия земли постановили Совет
Elders decided uh for ritual purposes a young
Старейшин э в ритуальных целях молодую
girl like  14 years old Yes, this is PT I
девушку типа 14 лет Да вот это ПТ
look at this Not Peter I himself wrote Peter
I это смотрите Не сам Пётр I писал Пётр
did not issue a decree on the death penalty for
пе издал указ о смертной казни
cannibals Yes,
каннибалов Да
but Peter’s clerk
а писар Петра
Feofan Prokopovich Feofan Prokopovich
Феофан Прокопович Феофан Прокопович
may know this Yes, he wrote down
может знаете тако Да вот он записывал
these, there is also a
вот эти там ещ есть
chronicle on these cases, yes, and you  don’t you
летопись по этим делам есть да а вы не
think that all these chroniclers could
думаете что все эти летописцы могли
just have a
просто
girl there from hunger? No, look. The fact
там от голода девку Нет там смотри Дело
is that there are interrogations there because there
в том что Там же допросы есть потому что
was a trial. Yes, there was a trial.  I find it
был суд Да был суд судебный процесс
hard to believe please
целях верится с трудом мне пожалуйста
links to sources because I’ll
ссылки на источники потому что я же
tell you look Google Google then
скажу смотрите Погугли Погугли потом
Kansky practices
Канские практики
among all this was some kind of orphan
сре всего это была какая-нибудь сирота
and also mentally [ __ ] or
ещё и умственно отсталая или
some kind of eternal or something else,
какая-нибудь там у вечная или что-то ещё
this girl and they are mentally [ __ ]  I’m
вот эта девушка и они умственно
lagging behind Well, yes, what should we take care of before especially
отстаю Ну да а что беречь раньше особо
as if they didn’t care about the
как бы не
mentally [ __ ]? No, they didn’t eat the mentally
отсталых Нет не съедали умственно
[ __ ]. I mean that they didn’t really
отсталых Я имею в виду что не особо-то
take care of any disabled people there, well, a
берегли каких-то инвалидов там ну
premature baby was born.
родился ребёночек недоношенный
Well, let’s say Drobyshevsky is there, well, he died, an
Ну допустим там дробышевского ну он пале
anthropologist Yes, it’s really there  it was I
антрополог Да Действительно это там было
know how many thousands of years ago I don’t
знаю сколько тысяч лет назад я уж там не
remember there, but he told such a
помню но он рассказывал такую
story, in general, about the fact that we, as a species,
историю в общем-то про то что мы как вид
are quite
мы довольно
friendly in essence. Especially if this
дружелюбные по сути Особенно если это
matter concerns our family, and that is, they
дело касается нашей семьи и то есть там
found a grave there, there are some
нашли там могилку там какие-то
absolutely  the skeletons there are all
совершенно скелеты которые там все
kind of crooked braids,
какие-то кривые косы
incomprehensible, they were apparently brother and sister.
непонятные это были видимо брат и сестра
Well, of course, it’s impossible to establish now, but
Ну сейчас конечно уже не установить но
most likely, that is, they were there with a
скорее всего то есть они были там с
bunch of some kind of pathologies. There they
кучей кучей каких-то патологий Там они
most likely suffered there, perhaps from
скорее всего страдали там возможно и от
pain from diseases
боли от болезней
and  during their lifetime and they, in my opinion, were
а при жизни и им по-моему там было
something like 14-15 years old, when
что-то по 14-15 лет когда
in the end or not history is silent about them. Well,
их в итоге или нет история умалчивает Ну
in any case, they didn’t find any traces on the bones of
во всяком случае на костях не нашли
what was there, well, the meat of these steaks was removed,
следов что там ну откли мясо этих стей
it seems, as if for ritual purposes, they were
вроде бы как в ритуальных целях их
simply and  buried for ritual purposes
просто и в ритуальных целях похоронили
But by the way, the girl had
А вот а ну там кстати у девочки вот
this crooked braid, her
которая вот эта вот кривая коса у неё
mouth was still gagged there, because
ещё рот был заткнут там ну потому что
apparently she was screaming there so that she wouldn’t scream, they
видимо она орала там чтобы не орала ей
put some kind of gag in her mouth,
там кляп какой-то в рот вставили
uh A Most likely I  I think so damn they
ээ А Скорее всего я думаю так блин они
came up with such ritual purposes simply
ритуальные цели такие придумали просто
because these disabled people got tired of them and that’s it
потому что их эти инвалиды достали и всё
and they’re stupid to look after them
и они тупо за ними ухаживать
because but damn it’s true damn it in the
потому что но блин это правда блин в
conditions of the Stone Age somewhere there damn
условиях там каменного века где-то там
two disabled people who are sitting on your neck
блин два инвалида которые у тебя на шее
they need to be  they also feed something there and
сидят их надо кормить они ещё там что-то
keep an eye on them and, in general, they
е за ними следить и вот в общем-то
came up with these kind of ritual things,
придумали вот такие вот ритуальные штуки
I think that’s
я думаю именно вот от
why everything is in charge because well, I don’t believe
этого всё и рули потому что ну я не верю
that a person is a creature that
в то что человек - это существо
becomes spiritualized
одухотворяется
Yes, I really think  that it’s not
Да я действительно думаю что там не
possible there are ritual purposes.
возможно ритуальные там цели Есть же у
We have some kind of religious fanatics there
нас там религиозные какие-то фанатики
who are still
которые сихр
running around. But basically, Man is a
носятся Но в основном Человек существо
rather practical creature. And why should the meat
оно довольно практичное А что мясу
go to waste? So they kill this unfortunate
пропадать Вот они эту несчастную
girl, well, hiding behind
девчонку е Ну прикрывшись ритуальными
some kind of ritual purposes, in fact,
какими-то целями на самом
I think how  something like that, then
Я думаю как-то так потом ещё
Drobyshevsky said that the
дробышевский рассказывал что вопросик
question is a question, you’re like your old mother so you do
вопросик вы вы в свою маму старенькую
n’t have to
чтобы её не
support her. Yes, of course not, damn it.
содержать Да нет конечно ну блин
Guys, let’s now imagine a different situation.
Ребят а давайте теперь другую ситуацию
Well, because I have something to eat.
представи Ну потому что мне Жрать есть
And if there was no food,
что А если бы не было шка жать
Mom, I’m having a hard time  I can imagine
Мама я с трудом могу представить себе
total famine, but let’s say there was such a
тотальный голод но а допустим была такая
UC Yes, no, I wouldn’t have eaten it, I probably
УЦ Да нет я бы не сожрала наверно
want to see I’m from Tomsk in England And you’re
хочется видеть Я из Томска в Англии А вы
from Tomsk, Ukraine costs a hundred
из Том сто Украина
Damn, I don’t know, I’m
стоит Блин я не знаю я с историей
not familiar with the history of Ukraine at all. What does
Украины не знаком вообще А причём тут
the history of Ukraine have to do with it?  I
история Украины я вам про Ленинград
’m talking about besieged Leningrad and about
блокадный говорю а про Ленинград
besieged Leningrad Well, the thing is that Leningrad
блокадный Ну дело в том Ленинграде как
was just the knowledge of the anfa yes of the Moscow Ivanovo
нания были анфа да Московской Ивановской
region, of course it was in
области конечно это в крови было у
their blood Yes no no instead of in
них Да нет нет вместо вместо того чтобы
short in it instead of
короче в неме вместо того чтобы вместо
instead of making a riot yes Because
того чтобы сделать бунт да Потому что
when Stalin ate red caviar Yes, and the
когда Сталин ел икру красную Да и
Chechen Republic was against the party, which eats
ЧР проти против партии которая жрёт
butter, the parties had everything, the parties had everything,
маселко у партий всё было всё было у
and the grandmothers, shorter than each other,
партий а бабушки короче друг друга
tried to supply androflor Leningrad
андрофлор Ленинград пытались поставлять
along Lake Ladoga there with
по ладожскому озеру там с
grief and that’s it, and look about besieged
горем и всё и посмотрите про блокадный
Leningrad Yes, party leaders had all the
Ленинград Да партийные деятели имели все
products  only they weren’t in Leningrad; they
продукты только они же не в Ленинграде
were in Leningrad; there were no party
были в Ленинграде не было партийных
leaders at the time of the siege; there
деятелей на момент блокады нет как не
weren’t any; where did they go at the time of the siege; there
было А куда делись момент блокады там
weren’t any of the Shays; there weren’t any of the
никого из Шей как никого не было из
bureaucrats; and who was in charge of Leningrad?
чинуша А кто Кто руководил Ленинград нет
Well, to begin with, there are still products
Ну начнём с того что продукты всё-таки
were supplied and they were supplied to them in the
поставлялись и им они поставлялись в
first place Okay Well, what kind of
первую очередь Окей Ну какие там были бы
products would there be Well, people Yes, look at
продукты Ну вот люди Да вот это смотрите
the essence of andropharm
сущность андрофарм
and
а
by the way, a separate species Yes, these Andes
кстати отдельный вид Да вот эти анд
Separately Well, not that a separate species is a
Отдельно Ну не то что отдельный вид это
separate evolutionary branch Yes, homo
отдельная эволюционная ветка Да гомо
sapiens Drobyshevsky has now simply
сапиенса дробышевский сейчас просто
lost
потерял
Drobyshevsky’s consciousness works with fossil
сознание дробышевский с ископаемыми
forms and we work with real ones.
формами работает а мы с реальными
Well, you haven’t noticed? Yes, that
Ну вы не замечали Да
something is, in short, I need to be
что-что то есть короче мне нужно
wary of the Muscovites, otherwise they will
опасаться москвичей а то
come; good logic, you
придут хорошая логика вы
understand. The thing is that for now So that’s
поняли Дело в том что пока Так вот
why these are all so many PMCs Wagner is
почему вот эти все так всякие чвк Вагнер
also the one  look there, he
тоже тот смотрите там тот какую-то там
beat up some kind of victim, there’s also all sorts of stuff, it’s all
жертву избил ещё там всякие это же всё
Andropharm.
андрофарм
No, they’re just psychopaths. Well,
Да нет это просто психопаты Ну
anfa, we think that they’re psychopaths, it’s
анфа мы считаем что они психопаты это
just Andropharm. No, that’s
просто андрофарм
not the norm, don’t you think that, for example,
нет не норма не вы считаете что например
a wolf is a psychopath, he’s like a goat? If
волк он психопат он в козочку они бы
they weren’t  each other and simply wouldn’t
Нели они бы друг друга и просто бы не
live to see our
дожили до наших
days No, wait, it’s not just that they
дней Не ну подождите Они же не то что
can’t stand themselves You guys
себя не выдерживает Ребят вы там
teach knowledge there Why can’t stand it,
преподаёте зна Почему не выдерживает
look, we are scientists But if all this has
смотрите мы мы учёные Но если это же всё
already been proven Everything has been proven I don’t know what
уже Доказано всё Доказано Я не знаю что
you’re reading where  Here you are, who is an educational
вы где читаете Вот вы кто по образова
researcher,
ски иссле
look Richard Robinson Yes, Richard
смотри Ричард Робинсон Да Ричард
Robinson is the University of Cambridge, yes
Робинсон это университет кембриджа да
Tony Jackson is a university of the masses.
Тони Джексон это университет масса Уч
They recommended it, let's whatever you
зарекомендовали давайте как там Вы
said, Richard
сказали Ричард
Robinson, my chrome is
Робинсон вот у меня тут хром
stuck here, Richard Robinson Who is
завис Ричард Робинсон Кто
he,
он
an anthropologist, Cambridge University, I
антрополог Кембриджский университет Я
found Richard Guy,
нашла Ричарда ги
Wait,
Подождите
[ __ ] up  executive director not that no
[__] исполнительный директор не то нет
yake those seventy-five until his
яке те семдесят пятого года до своей
death in 2021 Robinson was the chief
смерти в 2021 году Робинсон был главным
executive officer of Slasti Corpo
исполнительным директором сласти корпо
No no that's not
Нет нет это не
that and you who I understand you in English
то а вы кто я понял вы английским
type in English type Richard
наберите по-английски наберите Ричард
Robinson
Робинсон
anthropologist so here
антрополог так тут
back Richard Robinson anthropologist
назад Ричард Робинсон антрополог
a
а
robins i robinson
робинс я Робинсон
wrote awards and almost education
написал награды и почти образование
emeritus teacher of
заслуженный преподаватель
logic selected publications lalala damn
логии избранные публикации ляляля это
there are a lot of publications
блин тут куча публикаций нужно наверное
I probably still need to
всё-таки мне их
read them because that’s what I’m doing I won’t
почитать потому что я так я не буду с
argue with you since I’m not a scientist Lovo
вами спорить поскольку я не учёный Лово
Moscow
московски
anfa
анфа
anfa Andra
анфа Андра
Yes, I’ll google that now
Да сейчас загуглю что
this is
это
Anfa
анфа
[music]
[музыка]
Arof, an ancient people of Eastern Europe,
ароф древний народ Восточной Европы
presumably Norse,
предположительно норского
which I don’t know, of Baltic origin, they lived
что не знаю балтского происхождения жили
supposedly in the interfluve of the upper
предположительно Междуречье верхнего
Dnieper and Don, translated from Greek,
Днепра и Дона в переводе с греческого
their name means further
языка их название означает далее
cannibals According to Herodotus Well, this is Herodotus
людоеды Согласно геродот Ну это геродот
Herodotus
геродот
Tamme also
тамме тоже
believes in
счита во
what they corresponded to Extreme backwardness of
что переписывалась Крайняя отсталость
development were engaged  cannibalism
развития занимались каннибализмом
Herodotus reports from the Tsar Well, Herodotus
геродот сообщает от Царя Ну геродот
reports what they
сообщает на что
dug up to which the Scythians turned for
выкопали к которым обращали скифы за
help in the fight against the peppers gave their
помощью в борьбе с перцами дали свою
history Herodotus places the Anfals between the
историю геродот помещает анфалов между
neuros the correlation of Andropharm cultures
невра соотнесение андрофарм культурами
the determination of their summer linguistic
определение их летно языковой
affiliation is difficult due to the
принадлежности затруднительно виду
paucity of information provided by Herodotus,
скудности приводимых геродотом сведений
in particular, quite a fortuneteller associated
в частности довольно гадатель связывали
both with  Dnieper Balmi by the bearers of the Dnieper
как с днепровски балми носителями Днепро
Dvina culture and with the bearers of the
Двинской культуры так и с носителями
Gorodets culture by the ancestors of the Volga
городецкой культуры предками волжских
nova, the Czech scientist Wilhelm Tomashek, I don’t
нов чешский учёный Вильгельм томашек не
know how correctly, proposed at the beginning of the 20th
знаю как правильно предлагал в начале XX
century the decoding of the name an Bustard in
века расшифровку названия ан Дрофа в
his lectures at the Yana University, he
своих лекциях в янском университете
suggests that this is a Greek translation
предлагает что это греческий перевод
of the Iranian, in short, this is some kind of general
иранского короче это какие-то вообще
mythical characters
мифические персонажи к антропологии
have nothing to do with anthropology,
отношения не имеют
well, here to science in general There is not a single
како ну здесь на науку вообще Ни единой
link,
ссылки
in short,
короче
for now this is
пока вот это
bing I am from the lantern of the rocks Richard Robins she
бинга я от фонаря скал Ричард робинс она
Google really people I am on
Гугли реально народ Я в Википедии
English Wikipedia Richard Robins Oh I came up with
английской Ричард робинс О я придумал
Richard Robinson And this is Richard Robins
Ричард Робинсон А это есть Ричард робинс
anthropologist She  when I found my eyes
антрополог Она когда нашла у меня глаза
popped out of my head, I think
на лоб полезли думаю
damn it’s just a Sign from above
блин это просто это Знамение свыше
ka American Anthropological
ка Американская антропологическая
Association Well, he’s not from Britain, he’s from
Ассоциация А ну он не с Британии он с
America Yes, yes, the
Америки Да это
State University of New York, New York
да государственный университет нью-йорка
at the University of New York, Yes,
в университете нью-йорка Да
anthropologist and anthropology at the university
антрополог и антропология в университете
North Carolina
Северной Каролины
Damn, this is what it means to always keep your
Блин вот что значит всегда надо держать
mark to the end, even when she’s googling,
марку до конца даже когда она гуглит
sitting with a poker face, like this And then
сидит с покер фейсом да типа это И тут
she finds it herself and you’re
она сама находит и ты
so real
такой реально
Oh damn, that was divine Yes, like
О блин это было божественно Да лайк
squeak comment for anfa Let’s write on th
писка комент за анфа Давайте пись на й
Instagram I’m not  I know what this is for
Instagram Я не знаю для чего це тоб Для
Why are you there to marvel at the otse y face Ale
чего тоб там дивитись на оце й фейс Але
for you tse one two or three clicks Ale
для тебе це один два або три клика Але
you trime me me and I will say Wow in
ты тримае мене и я буду казати Вау в
me there are a bunch of fouls and in me there will be a
мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
classy mood to robiti Novi cool
класний настрий щоб робити Нови крути
video Write to  miy Instagram popk Andriy
видео Пиши на мий Instagram попк Андрий
like
вот
this, let me check for you
так давай я тебя чекаю